Jeeva R

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

jeevasmart82@gmail.com

7200712356

linkedin.com/in/jeevasmart82

https://jeevasmart.github.io

Summary

IT Support Engineer with 1 year and 11 months of experience providing Level 1 support to users via phone, email, Slack, and portal. Expertise in troubleshooting user desktop setups and remaining calm in difficult situations. Currently employed at Vectra Automation, Inc., where I am responsible for providing all IT support to users, including troubleshooting, Level 1 support, and end-user help desk support.

Through my current position, I have honed my skills in delivering end-user help desk support and have developed the ability to remain composed and effective in challenging situations.

Experience

VECTRA Information Technology Support Engineer

Vectra Automation, Inc.

Apr 2022 - Present (1 year 11 months)

Managed and deployed corporate PCs/laptops: configured new hardware, performed backups, diagnosed and repaired issues.

Analyzed, logged, tracked, and resolved user queries concerning User's Desktop setups.

Expertly configured WAN, LAN, VPN settings, and Port Forwarding.

Created SSL VPN users within the Fortigate Firewall.

Maintained and managed G-Suite admin activities, including user email ID creation and monitoring.

Configured IIS servers for hosting the nuget server.

Installed SSL certificates on IIS Servers to ensure secure web services.

Monitored and provided support for machines' accessibility through SSL VPN, TeamViewer or anydesk.

Implemented security measures by creating group policies to restrict specific permissions on desktops and set folder permissions for users.

Conducted general IT tasks: onboarded new hires, diagnosed and repaired end-user devices.

Performed and monitored remote server backups.

Managed endpoint security using McAfee and Symantec Endpoint Protection.

Maintained IT asset data: tracked serial numbers, software keys, and locations.

Conducted comprehensive system troubleshooting, documented system events.

Efficiently coordinated with vendors to resolve vendor-specific issues.

Coordinated testing, upgrades, and configuration of system files and services.

Demonstrated a strong knowledge of performance optimization for Windows laptops, including reconfiguration, maintenance, and upgrades

Founder - Self employed

Techsfy

Nov 2017 - Present (6 years 4 months)

1. System Installation and Configuration:

Installation of the operating system (OS) and driver updates.

Hands-on experience with Windows/Linux/Mac OS environments.

Windows OS installation, formatting, partitioning, configuration, and troubleshooting.

2. Hardware and Network Support:

Troubleshooting hardware and software issues.

Maintenance of CCTV cameras, unmanaged switches, and routers provided by the ISP.

Setting up and sharing network printers.

Troubleshooting and resolving client system issues.

3. Mobile Phones and Security:

Unlocking and flashing of all mobile phones.

Installing anti-virus software and removing viruses.

Education



Kings Engineering College

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer science Engineering 2017 - 2021

Arignar Anna Government Higher Secondary School

Higher Secondary School Certificate, Mathematics and Computer Science 2015 - 2017

Licenses & Certifications

- in macOS Ventura LinkedIn
- G Linux Tutorial Great Learning
- in Google Workspace Administration LinkedIn
- in Windows 10 for IT Support LinkedIn

Skills

IT Operations • Service Desk • Troubleshooting • Hardware Configuration • Computer Hardware Troubleshooting • Vendor Management • Asset Management • Analytical Skills • System Administration • Problem Solving